原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
《沼泽怪物》前情回顾
Previously on Swamp Thing...
你有看见其它有关我的使命的信息吗
Have you seen anything more about my mission?
你刚来玛雷的时候
When you'd first come to Marais,
你告诉我你做了笔交易
you told me you'd made a bargain.
直到被召唤  你不能离开这个镇子
One that bound you to this town until called upon.
离开玛雷
救命
Help!
你是什么人
Who are you?
只是个路过的陌生人
A passing stranger,
想要帮助你理解一些你已经知道的事
trying to help you understand the things you already know.
我就猜到你会来
Thought you might be coming around.
日志上写着那晚除了霍兰
Logbook says that there was only one other boat
只有一艘船开出去了
besides Holland's that went out that night.
这么说吧  对你家马特不太有利
Let's just say, it don't look good for your boy Matt.
没人能威胁我儿子
Nobody ever fucking threatens my son.
莉兹·崔梅恩
Liz Tremayne?
别再插手惹人生气的事了
You need to stay out of the pissing-people-off business.
莉兹
Liz!
滚开
Back off.
-你没事吧  -混蛋
- You all right? - Motherfucker!
丹尼尔  当心
Daniel! Look out!
亚凯恩找到的那份样本
The sample that Arcane recovered,
来自活的生物
it's from a living creature.
我们明早再谈
We'll talk about this in the morning.
你想让我推进这个项目  对吗
You want to me to push this project forward?
我要拿它做活体研究
I need it alive on a table to study.
找到它
Find it.
艾比  保护你的安全
It's very, very important, Abby,
对我来说非常重要
for me to keep you safe.
为什么
Why?
因为我在乎你
Because I care about you.
你几乎不了解我
You hardly know me.
你可能和一个人共度一生
Well, you can spend your entire life
却仍然形同陌路
with someone and hardly know them
或者你可能和一个陌生人相遇  就那么简单
or you can meet a stranger and... just like that.
你们心意相通
You get 'em.
我们之间心有灵犀
I felt something between us.
你不觉得吗
Didn't you?
那是实心的钢铁
That was solid steel!
悠着点  埃弗里要抓活的
Slow down. Avery wants him alive.
去他的
To hell with that.
我才不会为别人送死
I ain't getting my ass mauled for nobody.
什么东西能干出这种事
What the hell could do that?
不管是什么  我们给它注射的
Whatever it is, it's jacked up
氯胺酮都足够放倒一整个动物园了
on enough ketamine to take down a fuckin' zoo.
天哪
Jesus...
老天  那是什么
Christ! What is that?
打不倒它
It's not going down!
快  回船上去  快跑
Quick! Get to the boat! Run!
他妈的怎么回事
What the hell is happening?
快跑
Quick! Run!
上船
Get on the boat!
翻译  布塔
翻译  DustD
翻译  冰岛豆腐
翻译  Serrino
翻译  SwampSide152
翻译  DerbyNinja
翻译  余欢
翻译  马丁马丁回音山
翻译  小酸奶
时间轴  紫夏
时间轴  西·查
校对  布塔开花了
后期  渔夫
字幕总监制  布塔
沼泽   怪物
第一季  第六集
我得到消息的时候
I was making sure Susie was safe
正在安排苏西和亲戚安全在一起
with relatives when I heard.
我...我还是不敢相信
I... I still can't believe this.
没有我们能联系的人吗
And there's no one we can call?
家人  朋友
Family? Friends?
我在他的店里发现了一个旧名片盒
Found what I think was an old Rolodex in his shop
里面全是被划掉的洛杉矶号码
full of scratched-out LA numbers.
根据他的备注
From his notes,
大部分是经纪人和以前的冲浪伙伴
they're mostly agents and old surf buddies.
呼吸机维持着他的呼吸  但是...
Well, the ventilator's keeping him breathing, but, um...
他的大脑活动微乎其微
His brain activity is... it's minimal.
根据这些检查结果
Based on these tests,
我不确定他能不能醒过来
I'm not sure he's gonna come out of this.
我惊动了熊
I poked the bear.
这是我的错  知道吗
It's my fault, you know.
不  莉兹
No, Liz.
你说你和卡西迪被抢劫了
You said you and Cassidy were mugged.
这不是你的错
It's not your fault.
嗯  你昨晚太忙了
Yeah, well, you were dealing with a lot last night.
什么意思
What do you mean?
袭击我们的那两个混蛋
Those assholes that came at us,
那是个信息
that was a message.
别惹埃弗里·桑德兰
Don't fuck with Avery Sunderland.
埃弗里
Avery.
那混蛋威胁了我爸
The bastard threatened my dad.
我不肯收手
I couldn't let it go.
莉兹  这说不通
Liz, it doesn't make sense.
埃弗里喜欢你爸爸
Avery likes your dad.
如果他的女儿不再调查某些
He likes my dad even better when his little girl
肮脏的生意  埃弗里会更喜欢他
isn't investigating certain dirty business practices.
拜托
Come on.
没什么好惊讶的
Can't be that big of a surprise.
你跟警长说了吗
Did you go to the Sheriff?
我连写报道的素材都不够
I don't have enough for a story,
更别说指控埃弗里了
let alone to nail Avery.
这还要假设露西莉亚没被他收买
And that's even if Lucilia wasn't in his pocket.
我该怎么办
What do I do?
你什么都别做
You do nothing.
我按下删除  埃弗里收手
I hit delete, Avery backs off,
所有人都能全身而退
everybody walks away fine.
所有人  除了丹尼尔
Everyone except for Daniel.
埃弗里就在医院里  我去找他
Avery's here in the hospital. I'm going to find him.
艾比  别管了
Abby, let it go!
艾比  等等
Abby! Wait!
你是卡西迪  对吧  特技演员
It's Cassidy, right? Stunts?
对
Yeah.
我还在想制片厂什么时候会派人来呢
Was wondering when the studio would send somebody out.
你觉得我们今晚能拍好这个场景吗
You think we're even gonna get a shot off tonight?
按那个头号混球的演法肯定不行
Not if the D-bag at the top of the call sheet has his way.
抱歉  今晚太漫长了
I'm sorry. It's been a long night.
别道歉
Don't apologize.
我挺欣赏你的坦诚的
I appreciate the honesty, actually.
跟我说说
So tell me...
你觉得你感到满意吗
Would you say that you feel satisfied with things?
这里  在片场
Here? On set?
看看这家伙
Look at this guy.
这是他本周的最佳演技了
It's the most acting he's done all week.
天啊
Man...
可惜选角导演只把我当成特技演员
It's too bad casting only looks at me like a stunt man.
我可以为那个角色付出一切
I'd give anything to have that role.
嗯
Yeah.
我可以感觉到你的激情
Well, I can sense your passion, all right.
我在想
I wonder...
或许我可以为你美言几句
Maybe if I put in a good word,
如果你能帮我一个忙的话
you might wanna do me a favor.
帮忙
A favor?
我们在努力  埃弗里
We're trying, Avery.
但是她拒绝接受药物
But she's refusing all medication.
我不在乎
Well, I don't care.
沼泽里发生的事敲响了警钟
What happened at the swamp was a goddamn wake-up call.
你是医生  你想办法解决
Now you're a doctor. You figure it out.
你给她用药  停止她的这种行为
You give her something that will make this behavior stop.
-好吗  医生  -好的
- All right, Doctor? - Okay.
埃弗里
Avery.
非常感谢  医生  保重
Thank you very much, Doctor. Take care.
你好  艾比
Hello, Abby.
天哪  你没事真是太好了
God, I am so relieved that you are okay.
别这样
Don't.
艾比  如果这是因为玛丽亚袭击了你
Abby, if this is about Maria attacking you like that,
我真不知道她是怎么了
I honestly don't know what got into her.
-真抱歉我当时没...  -住嘴
- I'm just sorry I wasn't there... - Stop.
你威胁了戴尔瑞
You threatened Delroy?
你  你派人袭击了莉兹
You... You sent people after Liz?
借过
Excuse me.
这些可是严重的指控  艾比
Those are serious accusations, Abby.
你想谈严肃的吗
You want serious?
卡西迪陷入了昏迷  可能永远醒不过来了
Cassidy's in a coma and he will probably never recover.
是的  我们都为那孩子的遭遇感到震惊
Yes, and we're all very shook up about that boy,
不过如果需要付医院账单
but if there are hospital bills to be paid,
我一向乐于援助
I am always here.
没错  因为这就是你的手段
Yeah, that's right. Because that's what you do.
你伤害别人  然后假装在乎
You hurt people and then you pretend to care.
没有丝毫的假装  艾比
There's no pretend about it, Abby.
我爱这个镇子
I love this town,
我也爱镇子里的所有人
and I love all the people in it.
仅限于对你有利或方便的时候
When it benefits you or when it's convenient.
我要是变成麻烦会怎么样  埃弗里
What happens when I become inconvenient, Avery?
你会派人来袭击我吗
Are you gonna send men after me?
-艾比  -别这样
- Abby. - Don't.
你怎么能这么说
How can you say that to me?
我一直把你当女儿啊
You are like a daughter to me.
我绝不会伤害你
I would never ever hurt you.
不
No.
不  曾几何时
No, do you know that there was a time
我会相信你这话
that I would've believed that?
但你已不是我从前认识的那个人了
But you are not the man that I once knew.
你一无所有时我接受了你  你就这么回报我吗
I took you from nothing and this is how you pay me back, Abby?
那些人是你派的吗
Did you send those men?
艾比
Abby...
回亚特兰大去吧
Go back to Atlanta.
那些人是你派的吗
Did you send those men?
你确定你想和我杠上吗
Are you sure you wanna cross that line with me?
亚凯恩医生请到急诊室
Dr. Arcane to the ER.
亚凯恩医生
Dr. Arcane.
我不再是17岁的小姑娘了
I am not a 17-year-old girl anymore.
你现在吓唬不了我
You do not scare me the way you used to.
离莉茲远点
Stay away from Liz.
艾比
Abby.
我会永远在乎你
I'll always care about you.
但如果你再这么指控我
But if you ever accuse me like this again,
我可不会那么宽容了
I won't be so forgiving.
你得来看看
There's something you need to see.
这两个人刚被送过来
These two were just brought in.
他们叫着说自己
They've been yelling about being attacked
被什么沼泽怪物攻击了
by some kind of swamp monster.
放开我  拜托
Get the fuck off me, please!
冷静  先生  我们想帮你
Calm down, sir. We'd like to help you.
你听到他们说实际看到了什么吗
Did you hear what they actually saw?
当时应该很黑  但是
Sounds like it was dark, but...
他们描述的基本就是你的霍兰先生
Their description sounds 90% like your Mr. Holland.
我不知道
I don't know.
不可能是他干的
He couldn't have done this.
艾比  你说他有时
Abby, you said there were times
会失去控制
when he seemed to lose control.
我知道  但我了解亚历克
I know, I know. But I know Alec,
如果这是他干的
and if this is him,
肯定有什么解释
there has to be an explanation.
但愿是合理的
I hope it's a good one.
玛丽亚·桑德兰的事件报告写完了
Finished the incident report on Maria Sunderland.
你还好吗
You all right?
雷米·德博阿的混蛋哥哥来认领尸体了
Remy Dubois' piece of shit brother came in to ID the body.
可怜的家伙  他
Poor guy, he was...
他哭得像个小孩
He was crying like a baby.
我不怪他
I don't blame him.
雷米脑袋上的弹孔
The round that I put through Remy's skull
一览无余
didn't... leave much to the imagination.
我相信不管发生了什么
Well, I'm sure whatever went down,
都是合理的
it was justified.
合理的
Justified?
我夺走了一个人的性命  马修
I took a man's life, Matthew...
出于自卫
In self-defense.
为了保护你
To protect you.
德博阿  他看见你了
Dubois, he fuckin' saw you.
-看见我了  我...  -闭嘴
- He saw me? I... - Shut up!
霍兰死的那晚  德博阿在码头工作
The night Holland died, Dubois was working the docks
你开走了一艘桑德兰家的船
when you took out a Sunderland boat,
崔梅恩的朋友发现的那块船体残骸
and that piece of hull that Tremayne's friend found,
上面有爆破痕迹和铅弹弹孔
the one with the blast marks and the buckshot holes,
残骸和霍兰的船匹配
it's a match to Holland's boat.
你开枪打了他
You shot him.
然后你用了炸药
And then you went for the dynamite.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
-你了解我的  -我也了解埃弗里·桑德兰
- You know me! - And I know Avery Sunderland.
霍兰肯定妨碍到了他
Holland must've been in his way,
所以他需要除掉他
which means he needed him gone.
于是他找了一个他可以信任的人
So he found somebody he could trust,
一个他知道会保密的人
somebody he knew would keep their damn mouth shut.
那现在怎么办
So now what?
雷米死了  霍兰的船的残骸
Remy's dead and that piece from Holland's boat,
实验室只会说结果不确定
the lab will just say it's inconclusive.
不匹配
No match.
还有其它麻烦吗
Any other loose ends?
我只是  我不明白
I just... I don't understand.
半个镇子的人任他挑选
He could've picked half this town.
但他选了你  为什么
But he picked you. Why?
天哪  马修  如果你需要钱
Jesus, Matthew. If you needed the money,
-我可以...  -你可以干什么
- I could've... - You'd have what?
可以从你的应急基金里拿几块钱吗
You'd have pulled a couple of dollars from your rainy day fund?
一个小镇警察能赚多少钱还要我多说吗
Remind me again how much a small town cop makes.
这不是我的问题
This is not about me.
对  这是你朋友埃弗里的问题
No, it's your friend Avery,
还有他手上能追溯到三十年前的
and the two-inch thick file he has on you
你的厚厚一摞把柄
going back 30 years!
怎么  你还没看过吗
What? You haven't read that one?
我强烈推荐  真是一本杰作
Well, I highly recommend it. It's a real beaut.
贿赂  收买
Bribes, payoffs,
甚至还扔给了你几具尸体
even a couple dropped bodies in your custody,
早在我来之前
long before I ever came on.
足以让你终身监禁
Enough to put you away for life!
狗娘养的
Son of a bitch.
我所做的一切都是为了你
Everything I did, I did for you.
别  别...
No, don't...
别赖在我身上
Do not put that on me.
桑德兰说得很清楚  如果我不帮他
Sunderland made it very clear what he would do
对付霍兰  他会怎么做
if I didn't go along with him on Holland.
你现在为埃弗里工作了
So you work for Avery now?
至少比跟他同床共枕要强
At least it's better than sleeping with him.
你明白他从你身上夺走了什么吗
Do you understand what he has taken from you?
我保护了你  这就是我做的
I protected you, that's what I did.
就像你一直保护我一样
The same as you've always done for me.
停下来  停下来
Stop. Just stop! Just stop!
你知道我在想什么吗
You know what I been thinkin'?
我在想也许是时候
I been thinkin' that maybe it is time
申请调动到其它部门了
to start applying to other departments.
莱克查尔斯  霍玛
Lake Charles, Houma...
我可以远离你  埃弗里
I can just be done with you, Avery,
还有这个恶心的镇子
and this whole... lousy town.
警长
Sheriff.
刚刚接到玛雷总医院的电话
Just got a call from Marais General.
几个沼泽猎人在莱顿角被一只
A couple of swamp hunters got attacked by a wild animal
野生动物袭击了
out on Layton's Point.
动物管理可以明早去处理
Animal control can handle it in the morning.
不  你今晚就去
Nope, you go tonight.
我他妈不想看见你
I want you out of my fucking sight!
你知道  在这行里
You know, in this business,
找人帮忙通常意味着...
when someone asks for a favor...
不  不是那意思
No, it's nothing like that.
一切光明正大
Strictly on the up and up.
我手上的事够多了
My plate's just pretty full.
还有很多项目需要监督
I've got a number of other projects that I need to oversee.
如果能在玛雷安排一个人就太好了
It'd be great if I could have someone here in Marais.
一个我能信任的
Someone I could trust who could, uh...
用得上的人
make themselves available.
你需要什么  又是特技演员吗
What are you lookin' for? Just another stunt man?
不
No.
不  你会扮演一个不同的角色
No, you'd play a different role.
当然是在这部电影之后
After this movie, of course.
主演吗
Starring role?
非常重要的角色
Very important role.
我暂时没有全部的细节
I don't have all the details just yet.
很快会有一个女人来玛雷
There'll be a woman coming to Marais soon.
你可以从她身上获得更多信息
You can learn more from her.
祝你好运  卡西迪先生
Good luck, Mr. Cassidy.
-卡西迪  -什么事
- Cassidy. - What's up?
制片厂受够了韦恩演的垃圾
The studio is fed up with Wayne's bullshit.
明白吗  他们准备及时止损
All right? They're ready to cut their losses,
除非我们立刻重新选角
unless we re-cast... like now.
你一直陪他对台词
You've been running lines with him.
他们看过排演
They've seen the rehearsals,
他们喜欢你的风格
and they like your style.
-所以...  -你要给我机会吗
- So... - You're givin' me a shot?
-出演《蓝魔鬼》  -是的
- At the Blue Devil? - Yeah.
那个制片厂的人去哪了
Where'd that studio guy go?
什么制片厂的人
What studio guy?
怎么...
What the...
丹尼尔
Daniel?
丹尼尔  你能听到吗
Daniel, can you hear me?
没事了  没事了
It's okay. It's okay. It's okay.
你之前被打伤了  但现在安全了  好吗
You got hurt in a fight, but you're safe, okay?
-我要烧起来了  -你没事了
- I'm burning up! - You're okay.
-我要烧起来了  -没事了
- I'm burning up! - Hey! It's okay!
没事了  没事了
It's okay! It's okay!
怎么...
What the...
我听到警报了
I heard the alarm!
我是怎么了  我要烧起来了
What's wrong with me? I'm burning up!
-他醒了  -你是谁
- He's awake. - Who are you?
伍德罗博士
Dr. Woodrue.
桑德兰的人  你是丹尼尔的医生吗
Sunderland's guy? Are you Daniel's doctor?
不是
No.
但我听到了动静...
But I heard the commotion and I...
不好意思  他是什么时候苏醒的
I'm sorry. When did he regain consciousness?
就刚刚  你看他  他浑身滚烫
Just now! Look at him! He's burning up!
去找护士来
Go get a nurse.
快去  我看着他  你快去找护士
Go now. I'll stay close. You go get a nurse!
快去
Go, go, go!
我做了笔交易  我做了笔交易
I made a deal. I made a deal.
那个陌生人说我不能离开玛雷
The stranger said I couldn't leave Marais
直到我达成自己的承诺
until after I fulfilled my end of the bargain...
卡西迪先生  你本来不可能醒过来的
Mr. Cassidy, you shouldn't even be awake right now.
救救我  医生  救救我
Help me, Doc! Help me!
-我要烧起来了  -救命  救命
- I'm burning up! - Help! Help!
伍德罗
Woodrue.
我拦不住他
I couldn't stop him.
我会通知当局的
I'll notify the authorities.
当局
The authorities?
卡西迪先生可能对自己和他人构成威胁
Mr. Cassidy could be a danger to himself and others.
等等...
Just...
我了解他
I know him.
给我个机会去找他  把他带回来
Just give me a chance to find him and bring him back.
亚历克
Alec?
无论你对那些人做了什么
Whatever happened to those people,
我知道你是有理由的
I know you had a reason.
他们跟你讲了那个
Did they tell you about the monster
袭击他们的怪物吗
that attacked them?
亚历克
Alec...
你是在自卫
You were defending yourself.
他们袭击了你
They were attacking you.
你所遭受的疾病
You are suffering from a condition that we...
我们都不了解
That we don't understand.
我知道你很害怕  也很沮丧
I know that you are frightened and frustrated.
我不会放弃你的
I'm not going to give up on you.
你还是亚历克·霍兰
You're still Alec Holland.
我还是吗
Am I?
这里的万物之绿带给我的共通感
I feel more in common with the Green in this place
我以前从来没有感受到过
than anything I've ever felt before.
万物之绿是什么
What's the Green?
我们还不知道那是谁
We don't even know who that is.
他们是来找我的
They're coming for me.
他们不会收手的
This isn't going to stop.
亚历克
Alec!
Alec?
很晚了  我累了
It's late and I'm tired.
-最好是要紧事  -是的
- This better be important. - Yes.
如果我理解无误
If I understand correctly,
我听说经你推荐去取活体样本的
I heard that the two hunters that you recommended
那两个猎人失败了
to retrieve the living specimen failed.
多谢提醒
Thanks for that information.
说完了吧  晚安  博士
You know what? Good night, Doctor.
我提起这件事只是因为你想要切实的东西
I only mention it because you had asked for something tangible.
来证明在我的研究上进一步投资是合理的
To justify further investment into my research.
我要的不是切实的东西
I didn't ask for something tangible.
我也不关心任何切实的东西
I don't care about anything tangible.
我要的是结果  伍德罗
I need results, Woodrue.
结果
Results.
好吧  也许你听说了
Well, perhaps you heard...
丹尼尔·卡西迪发生了一起不幸的事故
There was an unfortunate incident involving a Daniel Cassidy?
消息都传开了
Word gets around.
医生说他陷入了不可逆性昏迷
Doctors say he's in an irreversible coma.
是的
He was.
直到一小时前
Until an hour ago.
丹尼尔·卡西迪苏醒了
Daniel Cassidy regained consciousness.
他开口说话  行动自如
He's speaking. He has full mobility.
这件事对我来说很重要  因为...
And it's supposed to mean something to me because...
卡西迪先生遭受了严重的脑损伤
Mr. Cassidy suffered a grave brain injury.
康复的可能性几乎为零
Chances for recovery were virtually nil.
直到我插手了
Until I intervened.
你在说什么
What the hell you talkin' about?
诱变性再生
Mutagenic regeneration.
你看
Here.
我合成了你的亚凯恩医生给我的样本
I synthesized the sample that was given to me by your Dr. Arcane.
然后给卡西迪先生注射了
I had it administered to Mr. Cassidy.
记住
Now, remember...
他的病情很严重
His condition was grave.
但是注射诱变剂后几个小时
But within hours of receiving the mutagen,
他的大脑似乎再生到了
it appears that his brain regenerated
完全恢复意识的程度
to the point of full consciousness.
这都是因为你用艾比从沼泽里拿来的样本
And this happened because you spun a magic potion
制作了一种魔法药水
from the sample Abby took out of the swamp.
你想要结果  桑德兰先生
You asked for results, Mr. Sunderland.
我现在就给你...
I'm giving you...
一项能改变世界的发现
a discovery that could change the world.
你唤醒了昏迷的病人
You woke a man from a coma.
这会引人瞩目
That'll get attention.
的确
Indeed.
那么
Well...
我去准备试验方案...
I'll prepare a testing regimen...
不不不  医生  你要的做的是
No, no, no, what you're gonna do, Doctor,
把你的发现写成一份报告  今晚就写
you're gonna write a report on your findings tonight, now.
我不明白这上面写的东西
I don't understand what anything says right there,
但你要写一份报告
but you're gonna make a report,
你要把所有能找到的图表和彩图
and you're gonna add every damn graph and colored picture
都加进去  但必须语言简练
you can find, but use short words.
这是我出资的研究
When I'm on the other end of the transaction,
必须这样
I insist on it.
与此同时
In the interim,
还有其它一些东西对未来的研究有价值
there is something else that could be of value going forward.
继续说
Go on.
亚凯恩医生  到目前为止
Dr. Arcane. She has, to this point,
她一直不愿意完全分享信息
been reluctant to fully share information.
告诉我你需要艾比的什么东西
You tell me what you need from Abby,
我会给你弄来
and I'll get it for you.
猎人说他们在这附近
The hunters said they came across
发现了一些踪迹
some tracks somewhere around here.
这里太他妈偏僻了
It's the goddamn middle of nowhere.
可不是吗
Tell me about it.
好了
All right.
四处看看
Take a look around.
尽量在雨水把证据冲掉之前找出蛛丝马迹
Try to identify any sign before the rain wipes it clean.
我们应该封锁整个区域
We should lock down the general area,
等天亮了再回来  然后我们...
we'll come back in the light and we could...
-把猎枪扔给我  -好
- Toss me that shotgun. - Yeah.
不管是什么  个头都不小
Whatever it is, it's big.
如果你看到了  要叫我
So if you see it, you call me.
我要跟着这些踪迹走
I'm gonna follow these tracks.
看看能不能把这东西赶出来
See if I can't flush this thing out into the open.
你开小艇
You take the skiff,
绕到这个水湾的另一边
get around to the other side of this inlet.
靠
Shit.
Shit!
天哪
Jesus.
我们来对地方了  保持警惕
We're in the right place. Keep your eyes open.
我可能有发现
I might have something.
艾比  你在这里干什么
Abby? What the fuck are you doing out here?
我可以解释  但我们得立刻回船上
Look, I can explain. We have to get back to the boat now.
不  你疯了  你来这里不安全
No, this is crazy. It's not safe for you to be out here.
-不  请听我说  -不  你听我说
- No, please just listen to me. - No, listen to me!
好吗  又有两人被袭击了
Okay? Two more people got attacked.
我们发现踪迹指向这里
We found tracks leadin' this way.
等等  你不是一人来的吗
Wait, you're not alone?
泰勒在船上
Tyler's in the boat.
你到底怎么了
What the hell is goin' on with you?
-艾比  快跑  -马特  别开枪
- Abby, run! - Matt, don't shoot!
别伤他
Not him!
亚历克  住手
Alec, stop it!
亚历克
Alec?
亚历克  求你了
Alec, please!
这是亚历克·霍兰
It's Alec Holland.
他还活着
He's alive.
不可能  这...这不可能
That can't be. That's... That's impossible.
-这不可能  -确实  确实
- It's impossible! - It's not. It's not.
我明白  我明白  我也解释不了
I know, I know, I can't explain it,
但是他活下来了
but he survived.
还有这片沼泽  沼泽...影响了他  改变了他
And the swamp, it... it affected him, it changed him.
他只是想要保护自己
And he's only trying to defend himself.
好吧  那么...那么...
Okay, so... so...
-霍兰还活着  -是的
- Holland's alive? - Yes.
我明白  我明白这很难接受
I know... I know it's hard to understand...
但这是事实
But it's true.
那他...他还记得什么吗
Does he, um... Does he remember anything?
比如那场爆炸
From the explosion or anything,
沼泽里的那晚
that night in the swamp?
那条船
The boat.
有人躲在暗处
Someone in the dark.
一道光
A flash.
我记得你
I remember you.
没事的  没事的
It's okay, it's okay.
你之前在桥边上
You were at the bridge.
你来帮助艾比
You came to help Abby.
马特  收到了吗
Matt, do you copy?
有发现吗
Find anything?
不  马特  不要
No, Matt, don't.
但我得...我得回复
But I gotta... I gotta respond.
不不不  不能让其他任何人知道他在这里
No, no, no, no one else can know he's here.
给我个救他的机会  求你了
Give me the chance to save him, please.
-马特  收到了吗  -求你了
- Matt, do you copy? - Please.
求你了
Please.
我是凯博
Cable here.
我以为有发现
Look, I thought I found something.
结果只是一头雄鹿
Turns out it was just a buck deer.
报警肯定是胡扯的
The call was bullshit.
我回原处和你汇合
Headed back to where you dropped me.
杰森  很晚了
Jason. It's late.
我  我还不累
I'm, uh... I'm not, uh... I'm not tired.
我  我马上就去陪你
I'll, uh... I'll be with you soon.
我想回家  杰森
I wanna go home, Jason.
我明白
I... I understand, uh...
等我完成这次报告就可以了
As soon as I finish this presentation.
一旦我们落实了这个项目的全部资金
Once we secure full funding for this project,
-我就可以离开...  -不是之后
- I'll be able to go... - Not later.
现在就走
Now.
今晚就走
Tonight.
我现在不能走
I can't leave now.
不  不能在我就要成功的时候
No, not when I'm so close.
怎么了
What is it?
你在烦恼什么
What's bothering you?
我无意听到你和桑德兰的谈话
I overheard you with Sunderland.
卡洛琳
Caroline...
我们有了千载难逢的发现
We made the discovery of a lifetime!
想象一下各种可能性
Imagine the possibilities!
这种治疗疾病的再生疗法
Regenerative therapies for disease that...
可能为医学带来突破性变革
That could revolutionize medicine.
要付出什么代价
At what price?
-什么意思...  -人体试验吗
- What are you... - Human experimentation?
你在受试人身上使用了未经测试的药物
You used an untested drug on a human subject.
杰森
Jason!
要是校务委员会发现了...
If the college regents find out...
校务委员会五十年来
The college regents haven't had
什么成果都没有
an intelligent idea in 50 years!
你是个受尊敬的教授
You are a respected professor.
我们已经有了美满的生活
We have had a good life.
不要为了埃弗里·桑德兰这种人弃之如敝屣
Please don't throw it away for a man like Avery Sunderland.
我
I...
我不能  我不能走
I can't... I can't leave.
-我不能走  -我知道
- I can't. - I know.
我不能走
I can't leave.
我知道
I know.
我只是不想失去从前的你
I just don't wanna lose the man you used to be.
蓝魔鬼音像店
丹尼尔
Daniel?
丹尼尔  我是莉兹  你在吗
Daniel, it's Liz. Are you here?
靠
Shit!
天啊  你没事吧
Oh, my God. Are you okay?
我在燃烧  莉兹
I'm on fire, Liz.
我要被折磨疯了
It's tearing me up.
我受不了了
I can't take it!
他肯定知道些什么  钥匙在哪儿
He's gotta know something. Where's the keys?
-我的钥匙呢  -你要去跟谁谈
- Where are my keys? - Who do you have to go talk to?
桑德兰的人
Sunderland's guy.
-那个医生  -伍德罗
- That doctor. - Woodrue?
是他  莉兹
It was him, Liz.
我们...我们先...
Let's... Let's just...
丹尼尔  等等
Daniel, hey.
-你还是滚烫的  -我得去找伍德罗
- You're still burning up. - I gotta go find Woodrue.
他知道些什么  莉兹
He knows somethin', Liz.
让我把你送回医院吧
Let me just get you back to the hospital!
靠
Shit.
-紧急电话  -我这里出了点情况
- 911. - Yeah. I have a situation here.
医生
Doc!
伍德罗
Woodrue!
医生
Doc!
伍德罗
Woodrue!
待在屋里
Stay inside.
锁好门
Lock the door.
医生
Doc...
-卡西迪  -医生
- Cassidy. - Doc...
卡西迪先生
Mr. Cassidy.
我受不了了
I can't stand this.
你的恢复十分惊人
Your recovery is truly remarkable.
我在燃烧  让它停下
I'm burnin' up! Make it stop!
我会送你回医院
I'll have you returned to the hospital.
检查会告诉我们是什么引发了这种这反应
The testing will tell us what's provoking this reaction.
他们做了什么
What did they do?
为了激发你的再生循环
Extreme measures were required
必须采取一些极端措施
to prompt your regenerative cycle.
他们是故意这么对我的吗
They did this on purpose to me?
是的  而且卓有成效
Yes, and it worked.
副作用出乎意料
The side effects are unexpected,
-但是起效了  -出乎意料
- but it... it worked. - Unexpected?
我要烧死了
I'm burnin' up!
我受不了了
I can't stand this!
杰森  救救他
Jason, help him!
你回屋里去
Get back inside.
-你不能不管他  -回去
- You can't leave him like this! - Go back!
你最好冷静下来  卡西迪
You better settle the hell down, Cassidy.
你得做点什么  医生
You gotta do somethin'. Doc...
他...你得让它停下
He... You gotta stop it!
别这么做
Don't do it!
最后警告  卡西迪
Last warning, Cassidy!
这就是你非凡的突破吗
This your magnificent breakthrough?
事实证明再生过程伴随着
There appears to be some unfortunate side effects
一些不尽人意的副作用
with the regenerative process.
不尽人意
Unfortunate?
这个人疯了
This man is psychotic.
他疼得发狂了
He's out of his mind with pain.
你自己看
Look at this.
我说过我还需要更多时间做试验
I said I needed more time for tests.
或许
Perhaps...
你应该延期会见投资者
You should postpone the investors
等我找到解决办法
while I find a solution for this.
我们不会做任何延期
We're not postponing anything.
就我的投资者而言
As far as my investors are concerned,
我们找到了圣杯
we have found the Holy Grail.
我希望你的报告能体现这一点
And I expect your report to reflect that.
警方交给我来对付
Now you let me handle the authorities.
我们会确保卡西迪得到他所需要的帮助
We'll be sure Cassidy gets the help he needs.
你真的觉得你能帮他吗
You really think you can help him?
他的变化超出了我的理解范畴
He's changed in ways I can't even understand.
现在他仿佛置身于一个完全不同的世界
It's like a whole different world is pulsing through him now.
-怎么不同  -他说有一些  一种...
- Different how? - He says that's something out there. A...
一种黑暗
A darkness.
他说这是一种我们从没见过的力量
He says it's a force unlike anything we've ever seen.
天啊
Jesus.
我知道  我知道你肯定觉得听上去很疯狂
Yeah, I know, I know this must sound so crazy to you.
不  我
No, I'm...
现在都开始习惯了
starting to get used to it by now.
很抱歉我之前一直没告诉你
I'm sorry I left you in the dark about this.
你不会有事吧
Are you gonna be okay?
嗯
Yeah.
我会交个报告  想办法搪塞过去
I'll just file a report, tuck it away somewhere.
谢谢
Thank you.
但我现在明白了
But I get it now.
你为什么总往沼泽里跑
The reason why you've been spending so much time in the swamp.
你为什么没和其他疾控中心的人一起离开玛雷
Why you didn't leave Marais with the rest of the CDC.
你还是能和我回去的  艾比
You can still come back with me, Abby.
不行  不行
I can't. I can't.
对不起  我必须帮助他
I'm sorry, I have to help him.
我们需要谈谈
We need to talk.
我知道你感觉被困住了
I know you feel trapped.
你的命运在八年前
Your fate was written eight years ago
就被你不可能理解的力量定下了
by forces you couldn't possibly understand.
你遇到的陌生人
The stranger you met...
他肯定在你身上看见了些什么
He must've seen something in you.
我知道  因为我也看见了
I know because I've seen it too.
我应该多告诉你一些的
I should've told you more.
但就算是现在  你的未来仍然不明朗
But even now, your future remains unclear.
你的任务  你被派到玛雷的原因
Your mission, the reason you were tasked to Marais...
仍有待揭晓
is still to come.
这点我无法改变
I can't change that.
但我喜欢你  丹尼尔
But I like you, Daniel.
比我那么多年来见过的
That's more than I can say about many
那么多人都要喜欢
I've met over my many years.
虽然我不能
So while I can't...
我不能干涉你的命运
I can't interfere with your destiny,
但也许我能帮你
perhaps I can offer you some...
减轻你所承受的痛苦
relief from the pain you're experiencing.
好好休息吧  丹尼尔
Rest easy now, Daniel.
这是我们之间的小秘密
We'll keep this our little secret.
你真是个好孩子
You're such a good boy.
光是有他就值得回来了
It's almost worth coming back just for him.
过来
Come here.
-谢谢  -嗯
- Thank you. - Yeah.
我们总是会来到这里  好奇怪
It's strange how we keep finding ourselves here.
我想找出新的答案
I want to find new answers.
我们还没有试过所有的医学手段
You know, we haven't explored every medical avenue yet.
因为有可能根本没有答案
It's because there's a chance that there are no answers.
我遗漏了什么
What am I missing?
拜托  拜托和我说说
Please, please talk to me.
有个陌生人来沼泽找我
A stranger came to me in the swamp.
我觉得他希望我仔细研究
I think he wants me to look more deeply
环绕着我的万物之绿
into this green that surrounds me.
但我不知道那样会不会使我
But I don't know how far that will take me away
离从前的自己越来越远
from who I was before.
离你越来越远
Away from you.
好吧
Well...
我还在这里
I'm still here.
你还...
You're still...
那是什么
What's that?
我不确定
I'm not sure.
亚历克
Alec.
艾比
Abby?